Let's talk about a new data structure called graph a graph data structure is a collection of nodes that
have data and are connected to each other.
Let's try to understand this through an example on Facebook.
Everything is in note that includes the user, the photo album, event guru page comment story, video
link note and anything that has data is a note.
Every relationship is an edge from one note to another.
Whether you post a photo, join a group like a page, et cetera, a new edge is created for that relationship.
OK.
This is a very important example to understand that graph graph data structure more precisely, a graph
is a data structure of V and E notation that consists of a collection of vertices called V and the collection
of edges e represented as order pairs of vertices it u v.
Consider this.
Three, zero, one, two and three.
So we have this is zero, one, two and three.
The edges.
Zero one zero two zero three and one two.
So the edges are zero one zero two zero three and between one and two, there is a bridge or an edge.
So with this connected, careful.
So this is the these are the vertices, this and this are the edges.
Therefore, this is a graph of V and E.
OK.
This is the invitation of aircraft data structure.
Let's learn about the graph terminology.
Consider the previously created the graph adjacency if Vertex is set to be adjacent to another Vertex,
if there is an edge connecting them, vertices two and the three are not adjacent because there is no
edge between them.
A path, a sequence of edges that allow you to go from vertex a divert x b is called a path.
So zero one one two zero two hour passes for Beth is from Vertex zero two passes the Vertex two OK,
so zero one one two or zero two out of the passes from the Vertex one if it's from zero to two.
So I can go from this Beth from zero passing through one to reach two, or I can go directly from zero
to two because there is a path between zero and two, or I can go from zero one and two to reach two.
OK.
And undirected graph is a graph in which the edge does not point in any direction.
OK, so like this graph, it is undirected a graph because we don't have flashes to indicate the pathway,
the only pathway of the data.
We consider this graph, but here we have the flashes.
We have these arrows, so it is a direct to the graph you see there in the previous video.
In the previous example, we don't have flashes, so it is undirected the graph zero can go to one and
one can go to zero, zero can go to two and two can go to zero.
Here it is, following the sense.
So a graph a direct to the graph is a graph in which an edge you v does not necessarily mean that there
is an edge v you as well.
The edges in such a graph are presented by arrows to show the direction of the edge.
So zero can go to one, but one cannot go to zero.
Zero can go to two, but do cannot go to zero and either two one zero can go to three, but three cannot
go to zero.
OK.
This is the director graph.
It follows the sense of the arrows represented to show the direction of the edge.
It connected, the graph is a graph in which there is always a path from a vertex to any other vertex.
This is the connected graph.
This is a graph in which always there is a path from a vertex to any other vertex, it is similar to
that tree, but it's not a tree tree of life means of trees.
OK.
No, the spanning tree is spanning.
Tree is a subgraph of any undirected graph connected.
The graph in which and includes all the vertices of the graph with a minimum possible number of edges.
Evert Evert Isthmus Then, if there's not a spanning tree, OK, we have a normal graph to the left.
This is connected.
A spanning tree.
We are connecting the edges for all the elements, except they are closed graph and spanning three can
be left to the right or like in this shape, like and or inverted.
OK.
This is the spanning tree.
Strongly connected components.
A strongly connected component is a portion of a directory graph in which there is a path from each
vertex to another vertex, it's applicable only on a direct to the graph.
So strongly connected components are applicable only undirected graph, consider this graph.
We have.
This directly graph, because we have the arrows.
And what is the strongly connected components?
These are the strongly connected components zero gives one, one gives two to give three and three give
zero again, so they form like a closed loop.
OK, so think about strongly connected component as a loop.
Other shape is forming four, five and six, so four, five and six.
They are strongly connect and then we have this small, strongly connected component, which is set.
So these are the segmentation of a graph directory graph or a strongly connected components.
Strongly connected components application like in vehicle routing, application maps and model checking
informal vertical.